morganlewis.com 2009-06-17

# EU Privacy Policy > Privacy Policy > About : Morgan, Lewis & Bockius - an international law firm

Morgan, Lewis & Bockius ("Morgan Lewis") is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. This privacy policy explains how we use the information we collect about you, the User, how you can instruct us if you prefer to limit the use of that information, and procedures that we have in place to safeguard your privacy. Please read the following information carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we treat it.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”) the data controllers are Morgan, Lewis & Bockius MNP of 68 rue du Fauborg, Saint-Honoré, 75008 Paris and Morgan, Lewis & Bockius LLP of 1701 Market Street, Philadelphia, PA 19103.

 **1\. The information we collect**  
When you engage Morgan Lewis's services or sign up for information services we may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Your full name, title, company, postal address, email address, telephone number, fax number.
  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our site, [www.morganlewis.com](http://www.morganlewis.com/) (the “Site”). This includes information provided at the time of registering to use the Site, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services. We may ask you for information when you report a problem with the Site.
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * Aggregate and user-specific information on which pages Users access.
  * Details of your visits to the Site including, but not limited to, home server domain names, e-mail addresses, Web browser types, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.

 **2\. Uses made of the information  
** We gather this information to allow us to process your registration and deliver you the service you require. The relevant information is then used by us, our agents, and sub-contractors to provide you with statements of your account and to communicate with you on any matter relating to the provision of your service in general.

We may also use aggregate information and statistics for the purposes of monitoring website usage in order to help us develop the website and our services and may provide such aggregated information to third parties. These statistics will not include any information that can be used to identify any individual.

From time to time we may provide your information to our customer service agencies for research and analysis purposes so that we can monitor and improve the services that we provide. We may only pass on your information to third parties with which we have a formalised Data Transfer Agreement.

We may also wish to provide you with:

  * information about special features of our website or any other services or products that we think may be of interest to you; and
  * related information with third parties we think may be of interest to you.

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing or other similar purposes, please send an email to [publications@morganlewis.info](mailto:publications@morganlewis.info).

 **3\. Disclosure of your information  
** We will not, without your consent, disclose to third parties any individually identifying information, such as names, postal and e-mail addresses, telephone numbers, and other personal information which users voluntarily provide to Morgan Lewis unless we have a formalised Data Transfer Agreement in place with such third party.

However, we may disclose your personal information to third parties if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply to our site Terms of Use.

 **4\. Use of cookies and other information gathering technologies  
** We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical information about our users’ browsing actions and patterns and does not identify any individual.

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. A "cookie" is a small piece of information sent by a web server to store on a web browser so it can later be read back from that browser. This is useful for having the browser remember some specific information. An example of when cookies can be used is when a browser stores your passwords and user IDs. They are also used to store preferences of start pages; both Microsoft and Netscape browsers use cookies to create personal start pages.

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of the Site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system may issue cookies when you log onto the Site.

When a user performs a search within the Site, we may record information identifying the user or linking the user to the search performed. We may also record limited information associated with every search request made by the user and use that information to, amongst other things, solve technical problems with the service and to calculate overall usage statistics.

 **5\. How we protect your information  
** Owing to the global nature of the Internet infrastructure, the information you provide may be transferred in transit to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA) that do not have similar protections in place regarding your data and its use as set out in this policy. By submitting your information you consent to these transfers. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Morgan Lewis enters into Data Transfer Agreements with third party recipients of information which are located outside of the EEA.

All information you provide to us is stored on secure servers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share this password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. However we have put in place various security procedures as set out in this policy. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

We also keep your information confidential. The internal procedures of Morgan Lewis cover the storage, access and disclosure of your information.

 **6\. Updating your details  
** If any of the information that you have provided to Morgan Lewis changes, for example if you change your email address or if you wish to cancel your registration, please let us know the correct details by sending an email to [publications@morganlewis.info](mailto:publications@morganlewis.info).

 **7\. Your consent**  
By submitting your information you consent to the use of that information as set you in this policy. If we change our privacy policy we will post the changes on this page, and may place notices on other pages of the website, so that you may be aware of the information we collect and how we use it at all times. We will also email you should we make any changes so that you may consent to our use of your information in that way. Continued use of the services will signify that you agree to any such changes.

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [publications@morganlewis.info](mailto:publications@morganlewis.info).

The Site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

 **8\. Access to information  
** The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. To access details of the information we hold about you please send an email to [publications@morganlewis.info](mailto:publications@morganlewis.info).

 **9\. How to contact Morgan Lewis  
** We welcome your views about our website and our privacy policy. If you would like to contact us with any queries or comments, please send an email to [info@morganlewis.com](mailto:info@morganlewis.com).
